# Ramez Sobhy Riad Ghaly

**♀** Giza, Egypt.

**\( (+20) 1000 977 568** 

ramez.ghaly@outlook.com

Please refer to the link for recent contact details



http://share.itweaver.com/cv/ramez.ghaly.pdf



#### **Brief**

Full Stack web developer with more than 8 years of experience in web solutions development, including user requirement gathering, analysis, solution design, database design and development, code implementation and publishing. I'm currently seeking an opportunity to further enhance my career.

## **Key Technical Skills**

- Web Development Technologies

Server Side		
C#	Java	Servlets
JSP	ASP.NET MVC	ASP.NET Web Forms
ASP.NET Web API	ASP.NET Web Services	ASP.NET Core
Entity Framework	MS SQL Server	MS Reporting Services
Client Side		
AngularJs	JavaScript	AJAX
JQuery	HTML	CSS
Ionic Framework	NodeJs Tools (gulp, grunt, etc.)	Photoshop Basics

- Hybrid mobile applications development using Cordova.

#### **Current Job Tasks**

- Conduct user requirements analysis.
- Design and develop databases for applications.
- Develop applications using suitable technology.
- Diagnose technical problems and apply appropriate solutions.
- Acquire new skills necessary for software development.

# **Employment History**

 Software Developer & Analyst, Information and Decision Support Center. (Cabinet of Egypt), Cairo, Egypt

November 2008 - Present

Collaborating in developing web solutions for internal systems and external front ends using variety of technologies and participating in all aspects and phases of development from the early stages of user requirement gathering and analysis till the solution is up and running.

- Software Developer, ITS-GBS, Cairo, Egypt

September 2008 - November 2008

During this small period, I took an initial training to develop applications for banking systems using SQLWindows (Gupta Technologies)

#### **Education & Qualifications**

#### May 2015

### **Australian Computer Society**

Accredited as "developer programmer" with qualification comparable to AQF Bachelor Degree with a major in computing.

September 2007 to July 2008

## Information Technology Institute (ITI), Cairo, Egypt

9 months Diploma in software systems development - Grade: A

2002 to 2007

## Ain Shams University, Cairo, Egypt

Bachelor of Electrical Engineering, Computer and Systems Department – Grade: 71%

Graduation Project - Grade: Distinct

Mobile Learning Environment Development using different software technologies (NET Framework & Adobe Flash). The project targeted personal computers and Windows CE PDA's.

## **Latest Training**

6 March 2017 to 28 April 2017

CDAC, Noida, UP, India

E-Governance Application Development

## **Projects**

Last Project: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=eg.gov.idsc.egaby

Used Technology: ASP.NET Web API, Microsoft SQL Server, Angular JS, Ionic Framework

As an analyst and developer at IDSC, I have been involved in many in-house applications development and maintenance primarily concerning back end development. Some of the projects I've worked with are:

- Helpdesk system.
- Attendance management system.
- Surveying system.

- Data migrations.
- Medical insurance management system.
- Mobile Apps Development using Cordova.

### Other personal achievements as a full stack developer:

- http://www.watani-sa.com 2011
- http://www.saudialyoum.com 2011
- http://www.freemoga.com 2009
- http://tanweer.itweaver.com 2012
- http://www.elkasr.itweaver.com 2013
- http://www.reflott.com 2013
- http://www.elghaly.com 2014

## **Other Technical Skills**

I have had the opportunity to work with diverse tools and technologies such as:

- Android development
- Sharepoint development
- .NET Mobile Applications
- C++, C
- Silverlight & Macromedia Flash
- WebsitePanel hosting

#### Languages

- Good command of English
  - IELTS Combined: Reading(8), Listening(8), Speaking(7.5), Writing(6.5)
- Arabic (native language)

#### Other Information

Notice period : 15 to 30 Days
Marital status : Single
Date of birth : 1/6/1982
Nationality : Egyptian
Current location : Egypt
Willing to relocate : Yes